<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Wondrous Items</name>
		<description>Homebrew Wondrous Items from Eclipse campaign</description>
<author>maeinomatic</author>
		<update version="0.0.2.0">
			<file name="items-wondrous.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/maeinomatic/elements-eclipse/master/eclipse/items/items-wondrous.xml" />
		</update>
</info>




<element name="Necrolace" type="Magic Item" source="eclipse" id="ID_Necrolace">
		<description>
			<p>While attuned to this delicate necklace, you absorb portions of the fallen spirits of the creatures you slay. When you reduce a Small or larger creature who is hostile toward you to 0 hit points, the necklace emits a faint glow and gains a charge. The necklace can hold up to 3 charges, and when found already contains 1d3 charges. As a bonus action on your turn, you can expend any number of held charges to release the souls and harness their energies to turn death into life. For each charge you use, you suffer 1d8 necrotic damage, and another creature you can see within 30 feet of you regains twice the amount of health that you lost. Damage you receive in this way cannot be reduced by any means. Being reduced to 0 hit points from the necrotic damage dealt to yourself renders you unconscious, but stable, and heals the other creature for twice the amount of hit points you had remaining when you used the necrolace.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">necro, momo</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>


<element name="Glove of the Aegis" type="Magic Item" source="eclipse" id="ID_GLOVE_OF_THE_AEGIS">
		<description>
			<p>This glove holds 5 charges and recharges 1d4+1 expended charges each day at dawn. When a target that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to expend any number of the glove's charges. For each charge used in this way you can add +2 to your AC for the attack, potentially causing it to miss. You can use this ability after the attack has been made but before any damage has been calculated.</p> 
			<p>The glove's power cannot be used if you are already wielding a shield.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">glove, aegis, reaction, momo</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">hands</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	
	<element name="Glove of the Grim Fandango" type="Magic Item" source="eclipse" id="ID_ECL_Glove_of_the_Grim_Fandango">
		<description>
			<p>Once attuned to the glove and wearing it on your dominant hand, musical tools come naturally to you. You have proficiency with all instruments, and after playing an instrument for longer than one minute, spectral forms appear beside you to accompany your song. The spectral forms are wispy and ethereal, but their illusory instruments complement your own. When you play an instrument for at least a minute, you have advantage on any check you make with it for musical effect. </p> 
			<p>You can use an action to play an instrument and cast one of the following spells from the glove: "fear "phantasmal force", "speak with dead". Once the glove has been used to cast a spell, it can't be used to cast that spell again until the next dawn. The spells use your spellcasting ability and spell save DC.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">glove, aegis, reaction, momo</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">hands</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a bard">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<element name="Sharkrazor Mantle" type="Magic Item" source="eclipse" id="ID_ECL_Sharkrazor_Mantle">
		<description>
			
			<p>You have a swimming speed of 60 feet and can breathe underwater while you wear this shark-skinned cloak. If a creature successfully grapples or restrains you by touching you, that creature takes 1d4 piercing damage upon that success and again at the end of each of its subsequent turns while it continues to physically hold you.</p>
			<p>In addition, the cloak magically sharpens your teeth. If you make a melee attack while underwater against a creature on your turn, you can use a bonus action to make a bite attack against that same creature if it's below it hit point maximum. This attack uses a damage die of 1d4, deals piercing damage, and uses your Strength modifier when rolling for attack and damage. The target can't be a construct, plant, or undead creature.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong> This cloak amplifies and sweetens the scent of blood to the point of distraction. Attuning to the cloak curses you until you're targeted by the remove curse spell or similar magic: removing the cloak fails to end the curse. While cursed, if you're within 60 feet of another creature that's below its hit point maximum, any attack you make against a creature who has all of its hit points, as well as any Wisdom (Perception) check you make, is made with with disadvantage. This effect only applies if the creature below its hit point maximum is neither a construct, plant, or undead creature.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">mantle, momo</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
<element name="Spellwoven Robes" type="Magic Item" source="eclipse" id="ID_ECL_Spellwoven_Robes">
		<description>
			
			<p>These robes are unique to the wearer and are spun from special, magic-sensitive threads. While wearing these robes, your AC equals 17. Whenever you cast a spell of first level or higher, you can also change the apparent style, color, and apparent material of the robe. Regardless of its appearance, it is always a robe and its weight remains the same. Glowing, arcane glyphs appear on the robe's fabric when you cast a spell before fading away a moment later. </p>
			</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">mantle, momo</set>
			<set name="category">Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
			<set name="armorClass">17</set>
			<set name="type">Armor</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="armor">Light</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LEATHER</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:armored:armor" value="17" />
		</rules>
	
	</element>	
	
	
<element name="Charming pink runechalk" type="Magic Item" source="eclipse" id="ID_ECL_pink_runechalk">
		<description>
			<p>Chalk One Up: As an action you can use this chalk to draw a simple symbol. A creature using this chalk must have at least an intelligence of 6 to draw these symbols. You can draw up to 20 symbols with this chalk before it is completely used up. </p>
			<p>Square:tunes and repairs instruments.</p> 
			<p>Circle When standing in the circle any music you play or vocal sounds you make sound three times as loud. :</p>
			<p>Triangle: Dramatic lighting fills a 10ft, increases any Charisma (Performance) checks by 3. </p>
			<p>Cross: Casts a small display of Prestidigitation fireworks when stepped on by any creature. </p> 
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chalk, momo</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Swamp green runechalk" type="Magic Item" source="eclipse" id="ID_ECL_green_runechalk">
		<description>
			<p>Chalk One Up: As an action you can use this chalk to draw a simple symbol. A creature using this chalk must have at least an intelligence of 6 to draw these symbols. You can draw up to 20 symbols with this chalk before it is completely used up. </p>
			<p>Square: a 5ft square becomes coated in a thick green gluelike substanse. Any creature stepping on it must make a Strength (Athletics) check (DS 9) to break free. It can repeat the check on it's turn. Only one square can be active at a time. Remains active for 24 hours. </p> 
			<p>Circle: coatss a weapon or one piece of ammunition in acid which deals 1d4 Acid damage on the first strike.</p>
			<p>Triangle: Conjures one empty vial. </p>
			<p>Cross: When drawn on a shield or armor grants Acid resistance for 1 day. </p> 
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chalk, momo</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	
<element name="Shared Burden" type="Magic Item" source="eclipse" id="ID_ECL_SHARED_BURDEN">
		<description>
			<p>This set of chained rings and bracers is a sign of the pact you forged with your patron. When you attune to the item, the small spikes that line the inside of the bands become harmless and feel like a warm, gentle caress against your skin. Once attuned, you can also use it as a spellcasting focus. </p> 
			<p>Whenever you would deal damage to a creature with a warlock spell or cantrip, you can choose to add your Charisma modifier (minimum 1) to the spell's damage. When you do, you take psychic damage equal to half your Charisma modifier (minimum 1), rounded up. This psychic damage ignores resistances and immunities.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">glove, warlock, momo</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">hands</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a warlock">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Book of Fedias" type="Magic Item" source="eclipse" id="ID_ECL_BOOK_OF_FEDIAS">
		<description>
			<p>A magical book describing the life and ascension of the god Electrolux. </p>
			<p>The book is magically infused with the power to grant one temporary Warlock Spellslot.Once per day you can spend 1 hour reading this book, roll a d20 against your own spellcasting saving throw DC, if you succeed you gain one additional Warlock spellslot for up to 24 hours. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">book, warlock, electrolux, fedias, momo</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>			
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Unique</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Kors mask" type="Item" source="eclipse" id="ID_ECL_KORS_MASK">
		<description>
			<p> A mask work by Kors to hide his skin.</p>
			<p>wearing the mask grants you a +1 bonus to Deception. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">mask, kors, deception, momo</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">25</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="deception:passive" value="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
</elements>
