<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Wondrous Items</name>
		<description>Homebrew Wondrous Items from Eclipse campaign</description>
<author>maeinomatic</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="items-wondrous.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/maeinomatic/elements-eclipse/master/eclipse/items/items-wondrous.xml" />
		</update>
</info>




<element name="Necrolace" type="Magic Item" source="eclipse" id="ID_Necrolace">
		<description>
			<p>While attuned to this delicate necklace, you absorb portions of the fallen spirits of the creatures you slay. When you reduce a Small or larger creature who is hostile toward you to 0 hit points, the necklace emits a faint glow and gains a charge. The necklace can hold up to 3 charges, and when found already contains 1d3 charges. As a bonus action on your turn, you can expend any number of held charges to release the souls and harness their energies to turn death into life. For each charge you use, you suffer 1d8 necrotic damage, and another creature you can see within 30 feet of you regains twice the amount of health that you lost. Damage you receive in this way cannot be reduced by any means. Being reduced to 0 hit points from the necrotic damage dealt to yourself renders you unconscious, but stable, and heals the other creature for twice the amount of hit points you had remaining when you used the necrolace.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">necro, momo</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>


<element name="Glove of the Aegis" type="Magic Item" source="eclipse" id="ID_GLOVE_OF_THE_AEGIS">
		<description>
			<p>This glove holds 5 charges and recharges 1d4+1 expended charges each day at dawn. When a target that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to expend any number of the glove's charges. For each charge used in this way you can add +2 to your AC for the attack, potentially causing it to miss. You can use this ability after the attack has been made but before any damage has been calculated.</p> 
<p>The glove's power cannot be used if you are already wielding a shield.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">glove, aegis, reaction, momo</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">hands</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

<element name="Sharkrazor Mantle" type="Magic Item" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_ECL_Sharkrazor Mantle">
		<description>
			
			<p>You have a swimming speed of 60 feet and can breathe underwater while you wear this shark-skinned cloak. If a creature successfully grapples or restrains you by touching you, that creature takes 1d4 piercing damage upon that success and again at the end of each of its subsequent turns while it continues to physically hold you.</p>
			<p>In addition, the cloak magically sharpens your teeth. If you make a melee attack while underwater against a creature on your turn, you can use a bonus action to make a bite attack against that same creature if it's below it hit point maximum. This attack uses a damage die of 1d4, deals piercing damage, and uses your Strength modifier when rolling for attack and damage. The target can't be a construct, plant, or undead creature.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong> This cloak amplifies and sweetens the scent of blood to the point of distraction. Attuning to the cloak curses you until you're targeted by the remove curse spell or similar magic: removing the cloak fails to end the curse. While cursed, if you're within 60 feet of another creature that's below its hit point maximum, any attack you make against a creature who has all of its hit points, as well as any Wisdom (Perception) check you make, is made with with disadvantage. This effect only applies if the creature below its hit point maximum is neither a construct, plant, or undead creature.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">saving throw</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>



</elements>
